翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
大家好
Alright, hello everyone.
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
！！真的有人看不到这行字！！
在这个视频中 我想向大家展示我偶然发现的一种新型恶意软件
In this video I want to show you the new type of malware that I've stumbled upon.
其实它并不算特别新
It's actually not super new,
已经存在好几个月了
it's been out there for months,
但它仍然在互联网上四处传播 之所以引起我的注意 是因为它看起来相当逼真
but it's still scattered around the internet and it
caught my eye because it seems kind of plausible,
如果你没有使用DNS广告拦截器或任何广告拦截扩展
And if you aren't using a DNS adblocker or really any adblock extension,
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
你应该使用uBlock
you should be using uBlock,
显然 Chrome通过Manifest版本3禁用了它
obviously, but I think Chrome banned it with Manifest version 3.
不过你还在坚持使用广告拦截器
And you should still be using an adblocker,
对吧？
right?
如果你不使用广告拦截器
Well, if you don't use an adblocker,
你可能会遇到这种情况
you might encounter this.
如你所见 我现在正在运行一个恶意软件 后台正在下载一个二次元塔防（Tower Defense）游戏
So, as you can see, I'm in the middle of a malware run right now
and there are anime TDs downloading in the background.
我是从某个该死的广告中得到的 我其实不确定它是不是恶意软件
I got this from some freaking ad and I'm not actually sure whether it's a malware or not.
*游戏名：胜利女神：新的希望*
我能下载吗？
I can download?
看看这个
Oh my god, look at this.
我能下这个二次元游戏？
I can get anime TDs on my computer?
9MB
9 megabytes.
我能相信这个吗？
Do I trust this?
但我们迟早会在下载时发现
But we're gonna find sooner or later when it downloads.
管它怎样呢
So yeah, anyway.
反垃圾邮件
Anti-spam.
正在检查与网站连接的安全性
Checking the security of connection to the site.
网站需要检查你连接的安全性
The site needs to check the security of your connection.
但与此同时
But at the same time,
你无法真正知道 因为现在大多数网站都在使用Cloudflare 而Cloudflare通常在网站加载时
you can't really know because most websites right now are using Cloudflare
and Cloudflare usually enforces a bug check
一开始就强制执行错误检查
at the very start when the site is being loaded.
这显然是在试图模仿那种状态
And this is clearly trying to mock that state.
首先 我不认为谷歌会这样做
Well, first of all, I don't think Google does this.
唯一会进行这种错误检查的服务商是Cloudflare 这算是在模仿它
The only provider that does this kind of a bug check is Cloudflare
and it's kind of mocking that.
你得点击复选框才能完成验证
And the idea is you have to click on the checkbox to fill it in.
那我们点击会发生什么？
So what happens when we click?
砰！
BAM!
你就会被重定向到恶意网站
You get redirected to the malicious website.
精彩
Amazing.
让我们看看这个网站的开发者控制台
So let's check out the developer console for this website.
就会发现它其实是假的
And see that it's actually bogus.
不是真正的验证系统
It's not a real recapture.
实际上 每次你点击页面主体时
And in fact, whenever you click on the body,
无论点击页面任何位置
anywhere on the body,
你都会被传送到这个“宝地”
you get resurrected to this gem here.
Limner's Little Shop.
实际上
And as a matter of fact,
我们可以复制这段代码 尝试在重定向之外运行
we can copy that and try running it outside the redirect.
看吧
And here we go.
会话已过期
Session expired.
但当我们点击这里
But when we click here,
哦对 还是会显示会话过期
oh, yeah, we still get the session expired thing.
没错 它显然被硬编码成会把你重定向到那个恶意小网站
Yeah, it's definitely hard-coded to redirect you to that little malicious site here.
我可以用自己的网站复现这个效果
I can make this happen with my site.
它能把我重定向到个人网站
It can redirect me to my personal website.
哦耶
Oh, yeah.
我可真是个黑客
I'm such a hacker.
其实还有另一种伪造网站版本 它伪装成Cloudflare
Anyway, there's actually another rendition of such a fake site
and it's impersonating Cloudflare.
记得Discord上有粉丝发过截图 是个虚假的Cloudflare机器人验证
I remember a fan on Discord sent me a screenshot
of a fake Cloudflare bot check and it was suggesting you download a
页面要求你下载文件才能通过验证
file in order to pass the bot check.
那可比眼前这个有意思多了
And that is definitely heaps more interesting than this guy right here.
找到那个才是我最终目标
And that's my ultimate goal to find that.
这类恶意软件最特别之处在于存活期极短
What's really exceptional about this type of malware is how short-lived it is.
就像我刚录完这个网站 转眼间就再也打不开了
As in, I just finished recording and reviewing this website
and I can no longer get into it.
我再也无法重现那个虚假的验证码了
I can no longer generate that fake reCAPTCHA again.
即便我再次运行那个网站
And say, even if I run that website again,
直接显示“会话已过期”
it just says session expired.
它再也不让我进去了
It doesn't allow me in anymore.
所以 我这次纯粹是运气爆棚  而且没给任何可乘之机
So, yeah, I pretty much just got really lucky and I didn't take any chance.
我立刻就开始录屏
I started recording right off the bat and,
不过这一切都值得  因为接下来两三个小时  我都要寻找这样的“宝藏”网站
well, it kind of paid off because
I'll be searching for like the next two or three hours for another gem like that.
那就待会儿见
So I'll see you then.
跳过广告？
Skip ad?
*网易瞩目*
发生什么事了？
What is going on?
又是一个游戏
It's another game.
我给我的电脑申请了一个恶意软件
I have requested a malware for my computer.
不过不是这种恶意软件
Well, not this type of malware.
界面上叠着一堆弹窗...
There are a bunch of overlays that are...
(⊙o⊙) 又来一个
Oh, another one.
好的
All right.
所以现在又冒出来一个
So we've got another one just now.
而且这看起来也不太可信
And it's not really that plausible,
但我觉得 我们方向是对的
but I mean, we're on the right track,
你知道的
you know.
请验证您是人类
Please verify that you are a human.
请按照以下步骤完成验证
Follow the steps for verification.
点击此处进行验证
Click here to verify.
好的
Okay.
所以我们又遇到一个更有趣的
So we've got an even more interesting one.
所以按下Windows键加R键
So press the Windows button plus R,
按下Ctrl+V组合键 然后按回车键
press control V and press enter.
所以这里的陷阱在于  他们把一个恶意链接复制到了我的剪贴板  现在又诱导我通过运行窗口执行它
So the idea here is they copied a malicious link into my clipboard
and now they're asking to run it through my run box.
这肯定是个PowerShell脚本  要么就是MSHTA恶意程序
It's gonna be a PowerShell script or MSHTA.
有意思
That's interesting.
为什么是MSHTA呢？
So why is it MSHTA?
*MSHTA，全称Microsoft HTML Application Host，是微软Windows系统中的一个可执行程序，
用于执行HTML应用程序（HTA）文件。
可以被用于绕过某些应用程序控制解决方案，因为它在IE的安全上下文之外运行*
算了 直接运行吧
Oh, anyway, let's run it.
其实无所谓了
It doesn't really matter.
它肯定会下载些恶意软件
It's gonna download some malware.
肯定会干点什么
It's gonna do something.
肯定没好事
It's gonna do something bad.
CPU占用51%
51% CPU.
看来运行得很欢实啊
It must be doing great.
看 它启动了CMD
Oh, see, it started the command processor.
它启动了命令提示符
It started the command prompt.
来看看详情 选择列
Let's check out the details and select columns.
检查下命令行
Check out the command line,
看能不能找到
if I can find it.
好了
All right.
在哪儿呢
Where is it?
命令行
Command line.
对
Yes.
我想...快点
And I want to... come on,
给我...
give me...
CMD C 对吧？
CMDC, right?
文件是什么？
What's the file?
找到了
There it is.
我得快速进入临时文件夹查看这个批处理脚本
So I need to quickly enter the temporary folder and check out this batch script.
可能被混淆了
It's probably obfuscated,
不过无所谓
but it doesn't really matter.
确实混淆了
Oh, it is obfuscated.
不错
Cool.
就这些了
That's all we get.
完全看不懂
It's unreadable.
但它正在运行
But it's running.
正在我电脑上运行恶意程序
It's running some bad stuff on my computer.
具体是什么我不清楚
I do not know exactly what it is,
但肯定非常危险
but it's something really bad.
不是挖矿程序
It's not a miner.
绝不可能是挖矿程序（ner~~~~）
There's no way it's a miner.
PowerShell
PowerShell.
这里调用PowerShell要干什么？
What is PowerShell here for?
哦 哦 它还在从GitHub下载东西
Oh, oh, it's downloading something from GitHub as well.
等等
Okay, hold on.
属性？
Properties?
不对
No, wait.
怎么复制这该死的命令行
How do I copy the freaking command line?
有了有了
Yes, yes.
我就是要找这个
That's what I've been looking for.
现在终止进程 我们自己下载
Let's kill this now and download this ourselves.
我本来就想这么做
That's what I was trying to do.
好 我先结束MSHTA进程 然后...打开记事本
Okay, I'm gonna kill the MSHTA and I'm gonna... I'm gonna open Notepad.
找到这里的命令行
Find the command line here.
有意思
Interesting.
这是自动生成的吗？
Is this auto-generated?
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
哦 等等
Oh, wait.
会不会是这个导致下载失败？
Could this be the reason why it's not downloading?
不 这是个私有仓库
No, it's a private repository.
你看不到内容
You can't see what it is,
但确实托管在GitHub上
but it's hosted on GitHub.
选择GitHub托管的原因
And the reason it's hosted on GitHub is,
我猜是为了绕过杀毒软件
I think, because otherwise it would trigger the defender,
既然是从GitHub下载
but it's downloading from GitHub,
那问题出在哪？
so what's the problem?
抱歉画面晃来晃去
I'm sorry for throwing the screen around,
它正在下载zip压缩包
but it's downloading the zip file,
重命名为随机UUID
calls it a random UUID,
然后解压到另一个随机UUID
and then extracts it into another random UUID.
这两个UUID相同吗？
Are those the same?
是的 完全一致
Yes, they are the same.
然后就会删除文件
And then deletes it.
估计还会执行程序
I think it runs it as well.
我们来看看压缩包内容
Let's check out what's inside.
DLL文件
DLL.
其实看不出什么门道
Yeah, you can't really tell what's inside,
但可以使用detected it easy检测一下
but I've got detected it easy.
如果是C#或.NET写的
If it's C Sharp, if it's .NET,
或许还有办法处理
we can probably do something about it.
哦 原来在压缩包里
Oh, it's in a zip file.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我犯蠢了
I'm stupid.
马上解压看看
Let me extract it real quick.
这情况可不妙
Oh, yeah, this does not look good.
相当不妙啊
This does not look good at all.
该不会还做了混淆处理？
Oh, could it be obfuscated as well?
我要运行试试
I'm gonna run this.
豁出去了
I don't care.
直接运行吧
Let's run it anyway.
反正就是要感染这台电脑
We're here to infect this computer.
它做了什么？
What did it do?
不如安装个追踪器看看
I mean, let's install it with a tracker and see what it does.
至少能监控部分行为
At least somewhat.
程序崩溃了
It crashed.
为什么崩溃？
Why did it crash?
因为是虚拟机环境？
Could it be because it's a VM?
别担心
Worry not.
我们用的是强化版虚拟机
We have a hardened VM.
再试一次
Let's try it.
还没运行
Not running yet.
好的
All right.
现在运行了
Running now.
控制流完全不同了
Oh, the control flow is different now.
这次差异太大了
Oh, this is so different now.
有意思
Interesting.
它做了什么？
What has it done?
这是当前用户的值吗？
Is that a value for the current user?
不清楚它的行为
I don't know what it has done.
简单说 他们给你一段shellcode  让你在本地机器上执行
Okay, basically, they give you a shellcode and they ask you to run this on your machine.
一旦你运行这个
And once you run this,
一旦执行这段shellcode
once you run the shellcode,
基本上就完蛋了
it's pretty much over.
一旦运行这个  你就真的中招了
Once you run this, you're actually infected.
所以大家千万要当心
So be careful out there.
这是个非常简单的落地页
It's a very simple landing page.
不知道能不能让Cloudflare的页面显示出来
I wonder if I can get a Cloudflare one to show up.
总而言之 我又花了一个小时  还是没找到仿冒Cloudflare的假验证码
All in all, I spent another hour and I couldn't find a fake CAPTCHA mimicking Cloudflare.
此外 过了那个阶段后  我再没遇到过任何假验证码
Moreover, I didn't get any fake CAPTCHA past that point.
这种情况相当罕见  但已经存在一段时间了
It is pretty rare, but it's been out there for a while.
我认为它如此特别的原因  在于其攻击性极强  本质上就是强迫用户执行shellcode
The reason I think it's so special is because it's super aggressive
and it basically makes the user run the shellcode
感染他们自己的电脑
infecting their own computer.
它可能在某天彻底消失
And it might go extinct at some point,
尤其是如果它模仿验证码的效果不佳的话
especially if it doesn't mimic the CAPTCHA well.
不管怎样 这些落地页大多都是凭感觉编写的  而且所有GitHub上的投放器都是自动化的
Either way, most of these landing pages are vibe coded
and all the GitHub droppers are automated.
这做法相当偷懒  但毕竟我们生活在生成式AI的时代
It's pretty lazy, but we're after all living the age of generative AI.
越是看似合理，越是危险
The more plausible it is, the more dangerous it is.
我想找到Cloudflare那个案例  因为整个页面看起来相当逼真
I wanted to find the Cloudflare one because it all looked pretty genuine,
但我只有一张截图
but I only have a screenshot.
原理都是一样的
The idea is the same.
原标题：New Cloudflare-Google Captcha Virus 原作者：Enderman
原视频上传日期：2025年7月30日
所以大家务必保持警惕
So stay safe out there,
别在电脑上随便执行shellcode
don't run shellcode on your computer,
我们下期视频再见
and I'll see you in the next video.
在 Youtube 上关注
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
如果你喜欢这个视频，请多多支持和评论哒~ o((>ω< ))o
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！